Kevin J. McIntyre

14371 Riveria Dr. Huntington Beach, CA 92647 (718) 249-5058 kevin70@yahoo.com

Architecture, Data, Design, Operations, Programming

Database

MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Postgres, Redis

Infrastructure

Amazon AWS, Backup/Restore, Disaster Recovery

J2EE

EJB, JMS, JTA, Hibernate, Servlets, SOAP, Spring

Script

Bash, JSP, Perl, PHP, Python, Ruby

Servers

Apache, Jboss, Nginx, Tomcat

Tools

Eclipse, Git/SVN, Junit, Linux, Maven, Ubuntu

UI

AJAX, FOP, HTML, POI, Javascript, JQuery, JSON

Objective

Seeking a position in software development, acting as lead developer, systems architect, project manager, or other business critical IT role.

Overview

From 1996 through 2000 my experience was in coding all aspects of the web with ASP, Perl, Cold Fusion, and MSSQL. Between 2000 and 2008 I focused primarily on open source technologies, with an emphasis on java, and J2EE development. Since 2008, I've deepened my exposure to and utilization of open source software, delivering efficient, and secure solutions across a variety of business needs.

As a member of a team, and part of an organization, I've always tried to be a fun dependable co-worker, believing that successful software is a combination of clear objectives, and team cohesion. My best work is on projects that I find innately scientific curious, either technically or from a fundamental business perspective.

My development philosophy is Agile based, preferring short sprints with tangible improvements that are easily integrated. I enjoy mentoring others, but am equally happy learning something new. My strengths are best utilized in both the backend and middle-tier conceptualizing business logic as sound, secure software.

Professional Experience

Senior Developer

Green Charge Networks

8/2011 -

Key contributor on flagship products Greenstation, and GridSynergy for Green Charge Networks. Lead development on prototype of event-driven embedded system controller using Python and Twisted. Device provided mitigation and curtailment of energy usage through control of inverter battery, photovoltaic, and electric vehicle charging systems. Monitoring was provided via reporting to Redis, and was controlled via GridSynergy network operations center, securely hosted in Amazon Web Services. Developed real-time charting system using Google Visualization, a tool used extensively during testing, operations, and new business development. Managed the release of multiple iterations of the software across the installation sites at 7-11, and Avis car rental. Contributor to corporate IP, authoring several patents on grid-tied battery control systems. Contributing developer on network operation J2EE software, using Mayen, Tomcat, Hibernate, Spring, and Google Web Toolkit.

Java Architect Freelancers Union 4/2008 – 2/2011

Lead developer on a medical portal for the Freelancers Union. Key member during project planning phase, advising on software infrastructure, researching solutions, and authoring project documentation. Implemented project using Eclipse, SVN, Maven, Xdoclet, MantisBT targeting Linux/CentOS running Apache, Jboss 4.2.3, and Oracle 11g. Developed standards-based enterprise application with hibernate model, a business-tier, and servlet/jsp controllers/views. Application featured services that serialized third-party EDI file into a data warehouse. Incoming data was subsequently audited and transformed

to a portal-tier. Web application featured SSO modules to view patient claims information on third-party websites written in OpenSAML and SAML 2.0. Developed administrative web application for call center representatives to view enrollment changes, and manage portal users. Responsibilities included porting application and data from Oracle to Postgres, and porting website from proprietary CMS to Ruby Webgen . Also, performed key roles through two billing/enrollment vendor transitions, contributing as quality assurance tester, business liaison, and lead developer spanning the lifecycle of the projects. Additional development duties included upgrades to multiple Frelancers Union web applications, development of member demographic sync with third party administrator, and writing summary of benefits / benefit booklet PDF generator using FOP 0.95 . Also contributed on projects Jobtrackr, Freelancers Union's Facebook application, Buzz Map , and explore insurance .

Senior Consultant Crunch Fitness 10/2006 – 3/2008

Engineered enterprise Swing application for an industry leading health club chain. Application featured JNLP WebStart client brokering calls via EJB SessionBeans to a server, running Jboss 4.0.5 and MSSQL 2005. Took ownership of source code (2500 source files/1800 sql scripts) and release cycle from 3rd-party vendor, responsible for all facets of development. Established a test environment, installed tracking software to manage bugs and feature requests. Participated in end-user focus groups, worked closely with management to identify priorities, and coordinated development schedule. Rewrote build scripts, leveraging Jboss Remoting to reduce client size and memory footprint. Refactored code to use Log4j and configured Jboss log4j.xml to isolate logging of specific functions, enhancing error monitoring. Stabilized server component by coding to J2EE standards, eliminating spec violations such as thread spawning, and non-final public static variables. Enhanced client, improving security using IP and MAC addressing, resolving cross-country latency issues while implementing or fixing bugs/features. Acted as DBA: modified schema to implement new features, wrote stored procedures using cursors and common table expressions, scheduled nightly jobs, lead initiative to boost database performance, and eliminated database locking. Additional duties included Cold Fusion development on the corporate sales website, and ASP.net development on the public facing website.

Software Developer *Iamplify.com* 7/2005 – 8/2006

Lead software development at Iamplify.com. Server administrator for linux servers running Apache2 (mod_php & OSCommerce), Jboss, Ruby, and MySQL. Project lead for embedded flash player initiative, and lead developer of associated reporting tool, providing key metrics such as registrations, purchases, and downloads. Lead development on co-branded storefronts (HarperCollins) written using Eclipse, Maven, and Xdoclet. Coded servlets, listeners, and taglibs, utilizing a custom templating engine. Developed deployment tool enabling designers and content managers to easily tweak, test and deploy each storefront. Additional duties included PHP scripting on fulfillment system, and development of media tools website .

Software ConsultantBlueprint 1/2004 – 2/2005

Consultant to Blueprint, a pharmaceutical branding company. Lead developer of application connecting doctors and patients. Established a data center, and lead development through multiple life-cycles, working with graphic designers and a junior developer. Coded application using Eclipse, Xdoclet, and Maven that featured a local EJB persistence model, EJB Session Beans, JMS communications incorporating 5 websites, and JAAS method level role association. Written with Xdoclet to be application server and database agnostic, and ran seamlessly on Jboss/MySQL and WebLogic/Oracle infrastructure. Additional duties included work on client websites such as Rockport, and DFKing.

Consultant *NYC Department of Probation* 12/2002 – 1/2004

Consultant to NYC Department of Probation, lead developer on automated probationer check-in system, managing 4 junior developers. Application utilized touch-screen monitor, and active-x controllers for web-cameras, palm-scanners, and printing. Developed using with Eclipse, Ant, and Xdoclet using remote EJB CMP Beans connecting to Informix database, JMS topics for probationer alerts, unit testing

with JUnit, and MVC architecture with Struts form handling. Additional duties included Cold Fusion work on intranet website.

Consultant *MTVi.com* 9/2000 – 3/2001

Consultant to MTVi.com, establishing Q & A methodologies, and lead testing on ecommerce initiative. Installed bug tracking software on Redhat 7.0, configuring Perl scripts to eliminate unused features. Wrote test cases, performed load testing, and mentored developers in best practices. Initiated weekly meetings to review bugs, and coordinate development and release schedules. Authored perl 404 finder to test targeted website for missing images.

Lead Developer Volatile Media 3/1999 – 8/2000

Lead developer for Volatile Media, owner of multimedia start-up EZCD.com. Responsible for production infrastructure of a custom CD burning service, featuring samples of music as well as game demos for creating a custom mixed media CD. Developed websites using MSSQL, Cold Fusion, and java services supporting back-end manufacturing. Developed mailing-list, calendar, and content management tools allowing artists to promote their music. Responsible for interviewing/hiring junior developers and managed aspects of a small office including networking, Exchange server, and ISP relationships.

Developer *Lexitrans* 10/1996 – 5/1999

Developer for Lexitrans, an online credit card transaction company. Coded and maintained state of the art membership billing system supporting 300,000 active members with real-time, and batch transactions using Cold Fusion, MSSQL, and X.25 communications for credit card authorization/transaction. Lead developer of call center software employing 150 people authoring html forms, db schema, stored procedures, and nightly scheduled tasks. Developed content naming convention and lead development of site scheduler for managing updates, mentoring designers in content creation. Participated in data center re-location and conversion from Cold Fusion/MSSQL to ATG Dynamo/Oracle.

Education

BS in Mathematics

University California, San Diego

6/1994